Chicken farmers in several Asian Nations
Are battling severe
Bird flu outbreak
The largest number of influenza cases is in Japan
And South Korea
In those countries
20 million chickens have been destroyed
Since November
Outbreaks have been reported
Over a wide area in Japan
During the past
2 months
Chiba near Tokyo
Has reported cases and there are reports of the disease
More than 1000 km away
On the island of Kyushu
Agriculture Ministry officials
Say fresh
Are still happening
We can't say risk of the further spread of bird flu
Has diminished
As the migration season for wild birds will continue
Until March
Or even April in some cases
Unofficial told
Reuters
The case was discovered in Japan and South Korea
Are similar to viruses
That spread through Europe
In 2019
Those viruses developed from widespread infections
In 2014
Sid Phillips
Class
He is an animal diseases expert
With the United Nations
Food and agriculture organization
Who is common in Asia
At this time of year
Because of migratory bird movements
Now new forms of the virus
Has evolved
To become more deadly in wild birds
This puts
Countries on flight Pathways at risk
Experts say
Last week
The a h5n8 virus reached
India
The worlds
Biggest poultry producer
Birds
Who has already been reported
In 10 Indian States
This is one of the worst outbreaks ever in India
Send Mohinder older I
An animal health expert and former advisor
To the FAO
He added that there is a lot of public
Fear about disease in Crows
Which can fly long distances
They know they fly far
And think they'll infect their poultry
Or even people
Chicken prices in India
Spell by almost
1/3 last week
As people became increasingly fearful of the disease
And stayed away from the meat
Bird flu cannot infect people who eat the meat
And the h5 N8 virus
Is not known to have infected humans
But people are still fearful
Send noodles a high
Chairman of Anand Agro group
A poultry company
Based in the Western Indian city of nashik
Indonesia is Asia's second largest poultry producer
The country is only a temporary Transit point for wild birds
This has reduced the risk of infections
An official at the country's agriculture Ministry said
However
Indonesia still to Ban live imports from countries
With h
5 + 8
Cases
And
Set up a surveillance
System
To look for early signs of the virus
With no major bird flight Pathways over Southeast Asia
Countries like Vietnam
Laos and Cambodia have so far not had H5
N8 outbreaks
Those Nations could however
Face risks from the movement of people and goods
The Asian outbreak comes as the world faces
The covid-19 pandemic
It hurt poultry sales early on
But the pandemic has also driven poultry demand up
As more people facing virus restrictions
Turn
To home cooking